<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Learning to program]]></title>
  <link href="http://cal47.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://cal47.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-04T10:37:25-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://cal47.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Christopher Loncar]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[End of week 3 and I know that I don't know a lot]]></title>
    <link href="http://cal47.github.io/blog/2013/10/04/end-of-week-3-and-i-know-that-i-dont-know-a-lot/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-04T09:56:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cal47.github.io/blog/2013/10/04/end-of-week-3-and-i-know-that-i-dont-know-a-lot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know that I&rsquo;m making progress and I&rsquo;m enjoying the process but I&rsquo;m starting to get stressed about finding the right job opportunity.  So this morning, on my commute in, I watched a <a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/kelly_mcgonigal_how_to_make_stress_your_friend.html?utm_source=email&amp;source=email&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_campaign=ios-share">Ted talk about stress</a> that made me feel better.  If you watch this, watch it to the very end.  The presenter is asked a question from a moderator (why Ted Talks need moderators&hellip;) and she has an excellent response.</p>

<p>I haven&rsquo;t been a student in a long, long time and I&rsquo;m finding it to be both fun and difficult!  I am not used to concentrating on learning for so long.  I&rsquo;m very good at being a top level thinker and seeing how different parts are put together, interact with each other, interact with users and how everything flows together.  However I&rsquo;m not [YET] very good at programming and it&rsquo;s somewhat frustrating.  I know the steps I would take to get from point A to point B, but I&rsquo;m so unfamiliar with how the technology works and still too inept at stringing together syntax to quickly or easily make my programs do what I want them to do.  I feel that in terms of my proficiency I&rsquo;m about in the middle of the pack but I have no way to gauge my progress relative to any &ldquo;norm.&rdquo;  I would like to know what I should be able to do at certain points as we progress through the program.  Like after the stackworld exercise (which was awesome btw, as it grounded how web applications are created and maintained through a tangible project), what should I be able to accomplish on my own at the end of this project?  I guess I feel that I&rsquo;m not progressing as fast as I should be.  More accurately, I&rsquo;m not progressing as fast as I want to.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Week 2 has come and gone]]></title>
    <link href="http://cal47.github.io/blog/2013/09/27/week-2-has-come-and-gone/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-27T10:04:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cal47.github.io/blog/2013/09/27/week-2-has-come-and-gone</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hard to believe that it&rsquo;s only been 2 weeks.  Feels more like 2 months. The pace is fast and it&rsquo;s been like drinking from a firehouse but I&rsquo;m making more and more connections.  I think the freeform nature of the projects is a good thing but it&rsquo;s challenging.  I feel like i&rsquo;m always trying to catch up and as soon as I understand and can implement a concept, something new and more difficult lands on my lap.  So I&rsquo;m constantly uncomfortable and struggling.  I think this is good.  I haven&rsquo;t been challenged or interested or interested in what&rsquo;s been challenging me in a good long while.</p>

<p>Having just walked out of our weekly group meeting I strongly agree with having some time to regroup and reinforce the concepts we&rsquo;ve learned by working alone.</p>

<p>My struggles are primarily language based &ndash; I don&rsquo;t know how to tell the computer what I want it to do very well.  I know exactly how I want something to work and I have a very strong high level understanding of how to solve problems and how the pieces should be put together but I&rsquo;m still weak in stringing together a list of commands and getting the syntax right. I&rsquo;ve started reading the Ruby Monk tutorial and I am finding it to be great at reinforcing concepts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2013-09-20-Week-In-Review.mdown]]></title>
    <link href="http://cal47.github.io/blog/2013/09/20/2013-09-20-week-in-review-dot-mdown/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-20T09:58:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cal47.github.io/blog/2013/09/20/2013-09-20-week-in-review-dot-mdown</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Week In Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://cal47.github.io/blog/2013/09/20/Week-In-Review/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cal47.github.io/blog/2013/09/20/Week-In-Review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>The week in review.</h2>

<p>I considered this week to be pretty fast paced and I realized that I was less prepared for class than I thought I was.  It was a wake up call.  I think that my code writing is about the middle of the pack at this point.  I know how to solve the problems conceptually but I don&rsquo;t know how to manipulate the code well enough yet.  I&rsquo;m struggling a bit with string &amp; array manipulation right now.  I just have to brute force my way through it and keep doing the TestFirst exercises until I grok it.</p>

<p>Having said that I like the pace.  It&rsquo;s fast and challenging and that keeps me motivated and makes me competitive within myself.  I really liked the pair programming exercise and I think that Eric and I worked well together.  I felt that he understands the language better than I did, while I understood how the parts should fit together better than he did.</p>

<p>Now about the coffee situation&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
