<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Learning to program]]></title>
  <link href="http://cal47.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://cal47.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-27T11:29:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://cal47.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Christopher Loncar]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Week 2 has come and gone]]></title>
    <link href="http://cal47.github.io/blog/2013/09/27/week-2-has-come-and-gone/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-27T10:04:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cal47.github.io/blog/2013/09/27/week-2-has-come-and-gone</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hard to believe that it&rsquo;s only been 2 weeks.  Feels more like 2 months. The pace is fast and it&rsquo;s been like drinking from a firehouse but I&rsquo;m making more and more connections.  I think the freeform nature of the projects is a good thing but it&rsquo;s challenging.  I feel like i&rsquo;m always trying to catch up and as soon as I understand and can implement a concept, something new and more difficult lands on my lap.  So I&rsquo;m constantly uncomfortable and struggling.  I think this is good.  I haven&rsquo;t been challenged or interested or interested in what&rsquo;s been challenging me in a good long while.</p>

<p>Having just walked out of our weekly group meeting I strongly agree with having some time to regroup and reinforce the concepts we&rsquo;ve learned by working alone.</p>

<p>My struggles are primarily language based &ndash; I don&rsquo;t know how to tell the computer what I want it to do very well.  I know exactly how I want something to work and I have a very strong high level understanding of how to solve problems and how the pieces should be put together but I&rsquo;m still weak in stringing together a list of commands and getting the syntax right. I&rsquo;ve started reading the Ruby Monk tutorial and I am finding it to be great at reinforcing concepts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2013-09-20-Week-In-Review.mdown]]></title>
    <link href="http://cal47.github.io/blog/2013/09/20/2013-09-20-week-in-review-dot-mdown/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-20T09:58:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cal47.github.io/blog/2013/09/20/2013-09-20-week-in-review-dot-mdown</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Week In Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://cal47.github.io/blog/2013/09/20/Week-In-Review/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://cal47.github.io/blog/2013/09/20/Week-In-Review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>The week in review.</h2>

<p>I considered this week to be pretty fast paced and I realized that I was less prepared for class than I thought I was.  It was a wake up call.  I think that my code writing is about the middle of the pack at this point.  I know how to solve the problems conceptually but I don&rsquo;t know how to manipulate the code well enough yet.  I&rsquo;m struggling a bit with string &amp; array manipulation right now.  I just have to brute force my way through it and keep doing the TestFirst exercises until I grok it.</p>

<p>Having said that I like the pace.  It&rsquo;s fast and challenging and that keeps me motivated and makes me competitive within myself.  I really liked the pair programming exercise and I think that Eric and I worked well together.  I felt that he understands the language better than I did, while I understood how the parts should fit together better than he did.</p>

<p>Now about the coffee situation&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
